# SEBASTIAN ALVARADO

www.linkedin.com/in/ska246801 | (956) 873-7201 | sebastianalyarado246801@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://ska246801.github.io/React-Portfolio/ Github: https://github.com/SKA246801/

#### INTRO

Sebastian Alvarado became a Full Stack Developer in a coding bootcamp at the University of Texas at Austin. He is an undergrad at UT Austin majoring in Computational Biology. Sebastian is constantly learning new things and is currently diving into cybersecurity. Through diligence and hard work, he was able to prove himself to the Directors of Seminaut Inc. and joined the board. Now, he is the Guild Development Director responsible for managing the entire development department on a day-to-day basis.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML/CSS, SQL, GraphQL

**Software & Frameworks:** Windows, Linux, Virtual Machines, Node.js, Express, React.js, SQLAlchemy,

Flask, Bootstrap, Material UI, Git, Visual Studio Code, Sequelize, GitHub, GitLab

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Cloud: Firebase

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Netflix Clone**

Live URL: https://sebastians-netflix-clone.herokuapp.com

- A clone of Netflix's online streaming service
- Uses the entire MERN stack
- There is an admin dashboard for CRUD operations of the site

#### **Amazon Clone**

Live URL: https://clone-39f35.firebaseapp.com

- A clone of amazon's online store
- Uses firebase, stripe, and React.js

#### **Instagram Clone**

Live URL: https://instagram-clone-8a613.firebaseapp.com

- A clone of Instagram's social media site
- Uses firebase and React.js

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Seminaut

Austin, Texas

Guild Development Director September 2022 - Present Managing the entire development department, including building out the structure, and planning out internship programs

Lead Front End Developer

June 2022 - September 2022

- Leading a group of developers in order to help them gain the experience they need to be successful
- Working on all aspects of the site to give the best consumer experience possible

Software Developer Internship

March 2022 - June 2022

A part of a team to build a website in order to connect the world of gamers

Austin, Texas

Learning Assistant August 2022 - Present

Assisting coding bootcamp students with their program errors

# **EDUCATION**

## University of Texas at Austin

Austin, Texas

Fullstack Engineering Bootcamp

August 2021

This is a certification course designed to give students full stack web development skills with technologies such as jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, React.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB and more.

# **University of Texas at Austin**

Austin, Texas

Computational Biology

August 2020 - Present

GPA: 3.4/4.0